I see sadness in your eyes.
悲しい目をしているね
Huh?
えっ？
Did something happen to you?
何か遭ったのかな
A beautiful girl such as yourself
shouldn't look so sad.
君のような美しい子がそんな不幸な顔をしているなんて
不幸とはただそれだけで罪なことだ
For being sad, in and of itself, is a sin.
Wounded humans are to be saved.
傷ついた人間は助けられねばならない
苦しむ人間は救われねばならない
Suffering humans are to be rescued.
Forsaken humans are to be loved.
孤独な人間は愛されねばならない
I'll help you forget about it.
忘れさせてあげよう
This medicine will make you happy.
幸福になれる薬さ
Hyoue died.
ヒョウエは死んだ
Relia ran away.
レーリアは逃げた
And that girl...
あの子は…
is human.
人間だ
And I...
僕…僕は…
I...
How was it, sonny?
どうだった？　坊主
That Book... Did you enjoy it?
あの「本」のことさ 気に入たかい？
I've got the next chapter!
続きもあるぜ
The one who stops is foolish
A piece of black wing gently touches fingers
If you were a story
You could still rewrite it all you want
The ink of blood doesn't dry up
No one knows the real us
What changes the chaotic world
What we pursued isn't
Small happiness
Fight with a rumbling heartbeat as a sign
What awaits you is infinite if you
move forward as you wish
Fight off no matter how many
times you get defeated
Engrave your dream onto the scar you bear
In order to connect today's memory that's
on the verge of being buried to tomorrow
Episode 3
Bombs, Humans, and the God of Death's Disease
第3话 夕阳与丝柔和克里欧
Welcome back.
お帰りなさい
Late night, huh?
遅かったですね
That girl's Book...
あの子の…「本」
We'll be together someday.
いつか　一緒に…
化け物！　あっち行け！
Freak!
Get out of here!
ここへ来るな　どっか行っちまえ　どっか行っちゃえ
Leave!
Scram!
Go somewhere else!
They do such mean things to you.
ひどいことをするねぇ
I dream... I dream about the future.
夢を見るの 未来の夢を…
That's why they're afraid of me.
だから 私のこと怖いって
Dreaming is a good thing.
夢を見るのは よいことですよ
What's your name?
あなたのお名前は？
Shiron. Shiron Byacornise.
シロン   シロン＝ブーヤコーニッシュ
Shiron Byacornise...
シロン＝ブーヤコーニッシュ
Let us go,
参りましょう 私と一緒に
together.
Go where?
どこへ？
To Heaven.
天国へ
All you need do is tell me what
you saw in your dreams.
夢に見たことを教えてくださればよいのです
Do so, and you can be happy.
それだけであなたは幸せになれます
I dreamt about a dragon...
竜の夢を…見たの
The dragon...
竜が  大きな水晶に閉じ込められた竜が
The dragon is encased in a giant
crystal and buried underground.
土の中に埋まっている
His Majesty was delighted to receive
the crystal of which you spoke.
例の水晶　国王陛下は大層お喜びでしたよ
Please continue to tell me
about your dreams.
これからも夢の話を私にお教えください
I'll give you anything you'd like.
何でも差し上げましょう
Anything... Just say the word.
なんでも　好きな物を…
There's an illness coming from the dragon!
病気が広がる
あの竜から
A terrible illness will spread!
ひどい病気が広がるの
So many people will die!
たくさん人が死んちゃう
Oh, very good.
おー　然様で
But I also saw how to make the antidote.
でも　お薬の作り方も見たよ　すぐに作って
Make it right away!
Wyzaf?
ワイザフ？
They're sick! Everyone will get sick!
病気なの　皆病気になっちゃうよ
あの竜をなんとかして!
Do something about the dragon!
Officer!
お役人様　王様の…王様の竜が…
The King's... The King's dragon, it's...
この未来は見えなかったようですね
You were unable to see this
future, were you not?
Your ability to see dreams is
not helping you, Princess.
姫様の夢にも　不便なものです
Our organization grows
throughout the world.
我らの組織は世界中に広がっているのです
You cannot escape our clutches...
逃れることなどできませんよ
我ら　神溺教団から…
You cannot run from the
Church of Drowning in God's Grace.
The ever-laughing magic blade, Shlamuffen,
「常笑いの魔剣」--シュラムッフェン
one of the seven war-machines of the
past, wielded long ago by the Gods...
遥かな昔　神々が用いた七つの追憶の戦機の一つ
It was right where you dreamt it would be.
姫様が夢見た通りの場所にございました
Excellent work indeed, Princess.
さすがでございますな　姫様
Bruising on his throat?
喉にあざが…
It's Dragon Pneumonia.
竜骸咳だ
死の神の病だ
It's the disease of the God of Death!
Is this true?
まことか？疫病に効く薬を作ることができると…？
You can create the medicine
that cures the plague?
Oh, saint...
聖女様
Oh, ever-laughing saint,
please give me the medicine, too.
「常笑いの聖女」様　私にもお薬を…
Are you sure it's wise to hand
Shlamuffen to her?
宜しいのですか？　シュラムッフェンをお渡しになるなど
Our savior needs a symbol that's worthy of her.
救世主には相応しい象徴が必要だ
Fear not. The girl lacks the
courage to oppose us,
案ずるな
あの女に我らに逆らう勇気などない
as well as the courage to end her own life.
自ら命を断つ勇気もな
We'll be together someday.
いつか　一緒に…
Defile thyself, Shlamuffen!
汚れよ！シュラムッフェン
What is the meaning of this?
なんと？
You waited for the illness to spread in order
to maximize profits, selling the antidote?!
では薬を高く売るために
病が広がるのを待っておったと言うのか？
Cut off her head!
殺せ！
Kill her!
Cut off her head!
殺せ！
Witch!
魔女を！
Ever-laughing witch!
「常笑いの魔女」を！
Off with her head!
虐殺でしろ！
Kill the witch!
魔女を殺せ！
All finished?
終わった？
I was waiting this whole time,
and you never moved an inch,
ずっと待ってたんだけど　全然動かないからさ
Colio Tonies.
コリオ＝トニス君…だっけ？
That is your name, right?
The innkeeper gave it to me.
ここの女将さんに聞いたわ
誰？
Who are you?
Hamyuts Meseta.
ハミュッツ＝メセタ
Treat me kindly, won't ya?
よろしくお願いなのよねぇー
Kill Hamyuts Meseta.
ハミュッツ＝メセタを殺せ
Kill Hamyuts...
ハミュッ…
You aren't gonna blow yourself up?
爆発させないの？
You are a bomb, right?
君　爆弾なんでしょう？
Okay, let's cut to the chase.
さっ　じゃ　本題
Colio,
コリオ君
gimme Shiron Byacornise's Book, 'kay?
シロン＝ブーヤコーニッシュの「本」  ちょうだい
Huh?
もう一つ持ってんでしょう　シロンの「本」
Don't you have another?
A fragment of Shiron's Book, that is.
No!
嫌だ！
Huh?
あれ？
Give it back!
返せ！
はずれ  たいしたこと書いてないわね
That blows.
Nothing impressive's written inside.
Give it back!
返せ！
My, my. Seems you really
grew attached to it, huh?
あらあら　すっかり気にいっちゃったみたいねぇ
Or...
それとも　シロンちゃんに恋でもしたのかしら？
Did you fall for Ms. Shiron?
恋？
Fall for?
It means to fall in love.
愛しちゃったってこと
No. That's not what happened.
違う　そんなこと…ない
Why not?
どうして？
I'm not human.
僕は…人間じゃない
だから　愛なんて
I could never love.
ふうん~~　爆弾だから？
Because you're a bomb?
In that case...
じゃあ…
これで君も人間よ
Look, I made you human,
コリオ君
Colio.
いた…
Oh, right.
なっ　君を操ってる奴がどこにいるか…
Do you know where the
man controlling you is?
Whoops. You wouldn't know that.
なんて  知るわけないか
Bye-bye.
じゃね
Okay, what's your next move,
Mr. Bomb-In-Love?
さーて　どうする？
恋する爆弾君
ふん！
Hamyuts Meseta is here!
ハミュッツ＝メセタが来た
Where do you think you're going?
Hamyuts Meseta is here!
ハミュッツ＝メセタが…
どこへ行くのかな？
My Book is going to Heaven!
わ…わたしの「本」は天国へ　神の身元へ
It will be with the Lord!
Heaven, huh?
天国ねぇ…
He's here.
いたー　へぇ
Oh, so you're the one pulling
the strings this time,
あんたが今回の黒幕か　シガル＝クルケッサ
Cigal Crekessa.
You can hear me, Hamyuts Meseta, yes?
聞こえているのだろう　ハミュッツ＝メセタ
The prologue has ended.
序章は終わった
The chapter of my magnificent
tale now begins.
今こそ私という壮大な物語の幕が開くのだ
It'd be too boring to let you end
it here, don't you agree?
こんなところで終わらせては  つまらんだろう
I'll make you into a lovely flower
to help color my tale,
お前も私の物語を彩る花の一輪にしてやるぞ
Hamyuts Meseta.
ハミュッツ＝メセタ
Ugh, nuts... A creepy guy.
嫌だ　痛い男
でも　まあいいわ
But it sounds like fun,
so I'll keep you company.
面白そうだし　付き合ってあげる
ふん！
Make my heart race, will ya?
ドキドキさせてよね
ここは代行の言ってきた場所か？
Is this the place the Acting
Director mentioned?
はい
Yes.
This is...
これは…
It's been a week.
一週間は経っている
And man, did they cut them up good.
しかし　見事な切り口だな
What kind of weapon did they use?
凶器はなんだ？
ミレボ　代行に連絡を
Milepoc, inform the Acting Director.
はい
Okay.
代行　例の帳簿に書かれていたブジーの場所ですが
Director, we're at the Bujuia City
location in your write-up.
皆殺し？　証拠隠滅ってやつ？
A massacre?
They're trying to suppress evidence?
マットアラストさんは
Mattalast thinks if that was the case,
they wouldn't have left the bodies.
それなら死体を放置していくはずがないと言っています
でしょうね
That's a good point.
分かった　調査を続けて
All right. Keep investigating.
了解
Roger.
He's got Dragon Pneumonia.
こいつは　竜骸咳
What?
喉が赤いあざ　間違いない
From the red bruising on his throat,
there's no doubt about it.
代行
Director.
I confirmed it. It's Dragon Pneumonia.
確認したわ
やっぱり竜骸咳ね
It's advanced, so there must
be others infected.
この分だと　感染者はほかにもいるわね
Also, I'm infected.
それに　私も感染した
The symptoms will present in a few
hours, and I won't be able to move.
数時間で発症して動けなくなるはずよ
We're also infected.
私たちもです
All the bodies here were infected
with Dragon Pneumonia.
ここの死体はすべて
竜骸咳の感染者たちでした
It looks like they were using the
corpses to breed the germs.
死体の中で菌を繁殖させていたようです
どうやら私たちは…
I guess we're...
...screwed.
嵌められちゃったみたいね
ミレボックさんたちが…
Milepoc and the others?
They got Dragon Pneumonia?
竜骸咳に？
They kept the fact that it's Dragon Pnemonuia
secret from the populace,
住民たちには竜骸咳であることを伏せ
単なる疫病発生として外出を禁止させたそうです
and simply forbade them from leaving their
homes as in a normal epidemic.
ノロティ　一人でどこへ行くの？
Where do you think you're going, Noloty?
I'm going to save them!
助けに行きます
Huh? What're you gonna do if you
get Dragon Pneumonia, too?
はー？　あんたまで竜骸咳に罹ったらどうすんの？
But...
でも…
Our first priority should be stopping
the disease from spreading.
今は感染の拡大を防ぐことが先決です
You are to isolate Toatt City with a barrier.
トアットの街を結界で封鎖するのです
Prepare to leave at once.
すぐに出発の準備を
But then Milepoc and the rest will...
でも　それじゃ　ミレボックさんたちを…
This is an order from the Acting Director!
これは代行の命令です
Noloty.
ノロティ
Volken!
ヴォルケン　あなたは図書館の守りを頼みます
You are to guard the Library.
That's not fair!
そんな！
それも代行の命令ですか？
Is that another one of the
Acting Director's orders?
Even if you went, you and the Acting Director
aren't getting along right now.
行ったところで
今のあなたでは代行とうまくやれないでしょう？
Use this opportunity to rest.
少し休んでなさい
You people stand no chance
of achieving happiness.
貴様らごときが幸せになどなれるものか？
I need it only for myself.
私だけでいい
I, alone, will become the most beautiful
Book this world has ever seen!
私だけが
この世でただ一冊の美しい「本」となるのだ
Slaughtering an entire city
with Dragon Pneumonia...
竜骸咳で皆殺し
Don't tell me that's how your
magnificent tale begins.
まさかこれで壮大な物語の幕開け？
Nah, that couldn't be it.
なわけないわよねぇ
How long will we merely sit here?
いつまで　こうしているんですか？
We can't just walk around, spreading
Dragon Pneumonia, can we?
歩き回って竜骸咳をばら蒔くわけにはいかんだろう
But...
しかし…
We're interrupting our regularly scheduled
programming for some breaking news.
ここで番組の途中ですが　臨時ニュースを伝えます
The large typhoon, Captain Chok,
expected to head northeast,
北東方向に指されると予想されていた大型台風「キャプテンチョック」は
has changed route and is heading directly
toward the southeastern Toatt City.
南東方向に進路を変え　トアット地方への直撃を加えてしました
What?
has changed route and is heading directly
toward the southeastern Toatt City.
トアット地方への台風の直撃は百年ぶり…
It has been a hundred years since a typhoon
directly hit the Toatt region.
Director! Director!
代行　代行
応答がありません
No answer.
The first typhoon in a hundred
years? That's ridiculous!
百年ぶりの台風？
そんなバカな
暴風は　代行の唯一の弱点です
Storms are the Acting Director's
only weakness.
She loses control of her sensory threads
and her hit rate plummets.
触覚糸を操れなくなるし
狙撃の命中率も下がってしまう
On top of that, when the Dragon Pneumonia's
symptoms present, she'll be unable to move!
それに　竜骸咳が発症すれば体も動かなくなります
今　敵に襲われたら…
If the enemy attacks now...
Shiron Byacornise's Book.
シロン＝ブーヤコーニッシュの「本」
Dragon Pneumonia.
竜骸咳
A typhoon.
台風
It couldn't be.
まさか…
下がれ　ミレボ
Get down, Milepoc!
Kill Mattalast Balory.
マットアラスト＝バロリーを殺せ
Kill Mattalast...
Kill Mattalast Balory.
マットアラスト＝バロリーを殺せ
Kill Milepoc Finedel.
Kill Mattalast Balory.
マットアラスト＝バロリーを殺せ
Those men!
この人たちは…
They're not men.
人じゃない　爆弾だ
They're bombs.
Kill Mattalast Balory.
Kill Milepoc Finedel.
マットアラスト＝バロリーを殺せ
They're trying to delay us here.
俺たちをここに足止めするつもりだ
But the enemy's true target is...
敵の本当の狙いは
Oh, I get it.
なるほどねぇ
シロンちゃんは今日のことも予言してたってわけ？
Shiron predicted this day would come.
The real target isn't the Dragon Pneumonia.
本当の狙いは竜骸咳じゃない
It's me.
このあたし
Well played, Cigal.
上出来ね　シガル君
Love?
恋…僕は人間になった
I'm human now?
That's not right. Humans are...
違う　だって人間は…
Beings with the right to gain all the
happiness this world may offer.
この世のすべての幸せを得る権利のあるもの
Wounded humans are to be saved.
傷ついた人間は　助けられねばならない
苦しむ人間は　救われねばならない
Suffering humans are to be rescued.
孤独な人間は　愛されねばならない
Forsaken humans are to be loved.
All humans are born into
this world to be loved.
すべての人間は愛されるために生まれてきたから
To love and be loved...
To experience fulfillment, never suffering...
愛し愛され　満ち足り　苦しむことなく
To live a life in utmost bliss...
至上の幸福に包まれた一生を送るために
I love you.
あなたを…愛しています
Calico?
ミケボン？
Wait a second, Calico.
ミケボン　ちょっと待ってて
Calico?
ミケボン？
Once again, I can't save anyone?
僕は…また誰も救えないのか？
Who's there?!
何者だ？
It appears there's no one here better suited
to pick up this story from where it leaves off,
この途切れた物語を紡ぐに相応しいお方は
あなたのほかにはいらっしゃらないようです
Master Volken.
ヴォルケン様
Right around here should probably do.
この辺りでいいかしらねぇ
I've kept you waiting, Hamyuts Meseta.
待たせたな　ハミュッツ＝メセタ
Help me add some excitement to my tale.
私の物語を大いに盛り上げてもらおうか
そっちこそ　楽しませてよね
You, too...
Let me enjoy this.
Lost the light
Before closing the sun
If it's a sparkling storm
Jump in before it tempts
The end comes to everyone one day
When the day comes
Aim for the future that begins to move
Even if it's already been written
Search and even acquire the
meaning of getting hurt
In order to be myself
The Setting Sun,
風が止む時
When the wind dies down, he discovers how
slender the woman's fingers are.
彼は彼女の細い指惜し
The Setting Sun, Shiron,
When the wind dies down, he discovers how
slender the woman's fingers are.
手を執る　夕日と地平線と交わる境界にへ
Hand in hand, they walk toward the spot where
the setting sun and the horizon become one.
夕阳与丝柔和克里欧
The Setting Sun, Shiron, and Colio
Hand in hand, they walk toward the spot where
the setting sun and the horizon become one.